Finding Aid for the Vanessa Brown Papers, ca. 1950-1988 LSC.1552
UCLA Library Special Collections
Vanessa Brown papers
1948-1991
UCLA Library Special Collections
Brown, Vanessa
LSC.1552
7.8 Linear Feet (5 boxes; 6 oversize boxes)
Vanessa Brown (1928-1999) was born in Vienna, Austria. She appeared in Broadway plays and films. In 1962, she became a writer-coordinator for the Voice of America. The collection contains books, scrapbooks, writings by Brown, and audio recordings.
Restrictions on Access
Stored off-site. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
COLLECTION CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. To review these audiovisual materials, you must notify the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk in advance of your visit.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Vanessa Brown, 1988-90.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 997094983606533
Biography
Brown was born on March 24, 1928 in Vienna, Austria; came to the U.S. in 1938; BA, UCLA, 1949; appeared in Broadway plays, As you Like it (1950) and The Seven Year Itch (1952-54); appeared in films, including Youth Runs Wild (1941), The Heiress (1948), and The Bad and the Beautiful (1952); married Mark R. Sandrich, 1959; became writer-coordinator for Voice of America in 1962; correspondent with Los Angeles Times Service, 1970-74, and National Public Radio, 1973-74; writer, KTLA-TV, 1972-74; worked for presidential campaigns of Adlai Stevenson, 1956, and John F. Kennedy, 1960; artist with one-woman show at Edgardo Costa Gallery, Beverly Hills, California; founder, American Acting Company. She died on May 21, 1999 in Los Angeles.
Scope and Content
The collection contains bibliographical reference works and other books in which Vanessa Brown is mentioned. Also includes scrapbooks, writings by Brown, and audio tapes of Voice of America broadcasts.
Organization and Arrangement
The material is in the order determined by the previous archivist.
Actors -- United States -- Archives; Motion picture actors and actresses -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; Women radio writers -- United States -- Archives.; Brown, Vanessa, 1928- --Archives.
- His Way: The Unauthorized Biography Of Frank Sinatra. by Kitty Kelley (Toronto: Bantam Books), 1986 (Box 1)
- Murrow: His Life And Times by A.M. Sperber (New York: Freundlich Books) [inscribed by author], 1986 (Box 1)
- The Papers Of Adlai E. Stevenson. vol.6., edited by Walter Johnson (Boston and Toronto: Little, Brown and Company), 1976 (Box 1)
- The Theatre In The Fifties by George Jean Nathan (New York: Alfred A. Knopf), 1953 (Box 1)
- Whatever Happened To The Quiz Kids? by Ruth Duskin Feldman (Chicago: Chicago Review Press) [inscribed by author], 1982 (Box 1)
- Periodical Cosmopolitan, March 1953 (Box 1)
- Photocopies of published biographical references to Vanessa Brown, 1962-1978 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1950-1962 (Box 1)
- Cassette tapes of classes, 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  Scope and Content
  Forty audio cassettes marked with dates and times of classes, the nature of which is unknown.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  FILE CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials in this file will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. To review these audiovisual materials, you must notify the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk in advance of your visit.
- Scrapbook, 1949-1950 (Box 3)
- Scrapbook, 1953-1954 (Box 3)
- Vanessa Brown Productions, 1984 (Box 3)
  U-matic videocassette "What To Be: a medley of six programs."
- Scrapbook, 1948-1953 (Box 4)
  Includes clippings and programs for a touring production of As You Like It starring Katharine Hepburn.
- Scrapbook, 1952-1953 (Box 5)
- Scrapbook, 1955-1956 (Box 6)
- Voice of America, 1962-1969 (Box 7)
  BOX CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials in this box will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. To review these audiovisual materials, you must notify the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk in advance of your visit.
  Contains: list of radio reports and interviews by Vanessa Brown; thirteen reel-to-reel tapes; interviewees include Robert Kennedy, Adlai Stevenson, and Billy Wilder.
- Voice of America, 1960-1969 (Box 8)
  Contains fifteen reel-to-reel tapes; interviewees and topics include Eleanor Roosevelt, Carl Sandburg, Adlai Stevenson, and Marietta Tree.
- Voice of America, 1961-1969 (Box 9)
  Contains fourteen reel-to-reel tapes; interviewees include Walter Reuther and Adlai Stevenson.
- "The Voice of America -- Where It Stands" [speech by Vanessa Brown], 1978 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- "Honesty?" [short play by Vanessa Brown], 1983 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Credits, circa 1955 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- What Do You Want To Be Tomorrow? [career-guidance workshop], 1988-1990 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- In My Father's House [manuscript by Vanessa Brown], 1975-1987 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Vanessa Brown Productions, 1978-1991 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Vocal Selections from Ben Franklin in Paris by Mark Sandrich, Jr. and Sidney Michaels [photocopy], 1965 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Photographs and drawings, 1953-1990 (Box 11)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes photocopies of photographs, drawings by Brown, pin-up from Esquire, Life, March 9, 1953 [with Brown on cover].